Right here, I am showing you a version of a sleeve that we call a long tabbed sleeve.
Oh, very creative and inventive.
Huh?
Because, that's exactly what it is.
It's a long sleeve that's fitted, like I showed you a fitted sleeve.
Or, you could do it a little bit looser.
I've shown a fitted sleeve with the seam lines down the center of each.
But, remember the center isn't the center necessarily on your drawing.
Because, you have to think about where the center is on the body and then put that into your drawing.
So we have, what makes it a tabbed sleeve is the fact that at the wrist line there is a tab.
And, typically it's going to button.
You're going to have a button hole and a button.
And, the tab is going to come from the inside going out or outside going in.
It really doesn't matter.
This one, we'll do inside going out.
And, you would take the fabric which we'll gather it.
Tab it, button it and then you have your fitted sleeve.
But, it does have a little bit of umph down in the bottom.
Because, the tab creates a tighter closure.